Guide to the Preservation Department, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Preservation Department, Yale University Library, records
1947-2015
RU 881
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
102.14
123.735
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and reports of the Yale University Library Preservation Department.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-C (YRG 32-C), Records of Yale University Library departments and offices.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and reports of the Yale University Library Preservation Department.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Academic libraries; Books -- Conservation and restoration; Born digital; Yale University. Library
- Preservation Department records, 1947-2002; Accession 2008-A-165
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038
  - Grants
    - NEH Grant, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Slideshow: In-house Binding, Care and Handling, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Environmental Survey Questionnaire, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - PMP (RLG Microfiloming Project), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - PMP III Grant Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Preservation Cost Study for Grant, 1984 and 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cost Model (Preservation), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - RLG Preservation RFP, 1987 and 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - RLG Preservation Microfilming Project, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - RFP, etc. Generic, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Six Month Report -- Master Copy, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - EHMP Proposal, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Western Americana Preservation Project: Grant -- Final Draft, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Western Preservation Project Grant: RFP, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - WAPP -- NEH File, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - EHMP File Holdings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - European History Microfilming Project: Final Grant Proposals, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - EHMP Quarterly and Six-month Reports to NEH, 1988-1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Grant -- Latest (NEH) (EHMP), 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - EHMP -- Paul's File, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berkeley (NEH Grant), 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Department of Education Latin American News, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Preservation at Yale Handouts, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Department of Education Latin American News, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Department of Education Latin American News, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - East Asia Project, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - East Asia Project, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - East Asia Project, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - GCMP I Quarterly, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Grant Appendices, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Streamlining/Automatic: Dec./Prep for NEH Grants, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - PC/CMDC Ad Hoc PMP -- Contin. Project, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - GCMP III Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Quarterly Reports GCMP III, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - RLG GCMP III Miscellaneous, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Students GCMP III: Jan. 92-Dec. 93, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - GCMP III Staff, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - GCMP III Proposal, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - GCMP III Statistic Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Mellon Grants (for Interns)
      - Mellon Intern -- Annual Reports, 1979, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Mellon Intern -- Recruiting, 1983-1985 and 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Mellon Intern -- Budget and Funding, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Mellon Major Grant Proposal (EHMP), 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Mellon Interns, 1993 -- Training, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Mellon Symposium 6/11/93, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Mellon Intern #1: Carla Montori, 1983-1984, 1993-1986 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Mellon Intern TenHoor Report: Kline Library -- Rare Collection Condition Survey, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous Documents, 1978, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Personnel
    - Conservation -- Asst. Conservator, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Walker, Personnel, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Pres. Div. Head -- Recruitment, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Personnel Candidates, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Workshops, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Professional Associations/Professional Development
    - ALA -- LBI -- Weiss Correspondence and Binders, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Energy Conservation -- NCAC, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Preservation Selection, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Internship -- Undergraduate, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Current RLC, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Good -- Swartzburg Draft, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Miscellaneous Loose Documents, 1981-1982, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - RLG Miscellaneous, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - CRL, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Cooperative Programs: CRL -- NELINET, 1968-1980 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Preservation Education, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - LBI, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - PMP -- RLG, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - RLG, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Pre-filming RLG, 1990, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - RLG, 1983-1987, 1986, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - BOG Selection -- Natl. Plan, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Contract -- Micropublishers, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Breakout: Environment, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Travel, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Workshops -- Pres. and Binding, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - A and A Task Force: RLG, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Acquisitions RLG -- STF Form, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - African Group RLG, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - RLG -- PC Annual Report, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - RLG BIBPAC, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Miscellaneous RLG, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - RLG, 1988-1989, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - RLG PC Binding, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Cancellation RLG STF Form, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Collection Development Committee, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Columbia -- RLG Preservation, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - RLG Consolidation of Backfiles, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Coordinated Preservation, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Coordinated Preservation - Old Petition RLG -- PC, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - E. European Special Interest Group RLG, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - RLG -- PC Emergency Planning, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - RLG Exec. Minutes, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - RLG Expenses CDC -- Items, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - (RLG and PC) Filming in Lieu of Loan Statistics, etc., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - RLG Gov't. Docs., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - RLG Jt. w/ CDC [sic] [RLG Joint with CDC], 1975 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - RLG Jt. w/ STF [sic] [RLG Joint with STF], 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - RLG Law Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - RLG Latin America, 1977 and 1979 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - LC -- Cum. NRMM and Coop. [sic] [LC -- Cumulative NRMM and Cooperative], 1975 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Master Copy RLG STF -- PC, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - RLG Memoranda, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - (RLG -- PC): Microfilm Funding, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - RLG Microfilm Master Policy, 1973, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Microfilming for RLG Mic. Pet. [sic], 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - RLG -- PC Microform Storage Joint, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - RLG Middle East, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - RLG Minutes of Meetings -- Pres Comm, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - NYPL -- RLG Preservation, 1971, 1973-1976, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Originals RLG, 1975-1976, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Other RLG Members, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - RLG -- PC Packaging, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - RLG Preservation Coordinators, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Pres Microf [sic] Petition RLG, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Preservation Task Force MH Support RLG, 1971, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Program Priorities RLG -- PC, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Public Services Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - RLG Readers Services, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Replacement of Missing Pages RLG -- PC, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - RLIN File #1, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - RLG Film Union List, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - RLIN File #2, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - RLIN Preservation, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - S/SE Asia Interest Group, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - RLG Serials Manual, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Serials Task Force (STF), 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - RLG Skipper, James, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - RLG Slavic Group, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Space Task Force, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - RLG -- STAC [Systems and Technology Committee], 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - RLG Travel, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - PMP, 1983-1984, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - RLG Benefits-Memo for MH RGW, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - RLG Serial Filming, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Archives and Manuscripts Microfilm, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Conservation Programs -- Columbia, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - RLG Statistics, 1971, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Survey Forms #12, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Preservation Dept Survey info CRL article, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Intern's Projects, 1981 Spring (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Misc Prof Develop. / Prof Assoc., 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Other Yale Records
    - Bibliophiles, 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Book Sale Signs, Circa 1970s? (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Cataloging, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - ILL Info., 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - Interviews, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - Stack Plans, Undated (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Electric Panel Info, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - dme (dmo??) DW [Environmental Surveys], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Assignment Plans, 1965-1978 (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Serials, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Serials Task Force, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Tricentennial [1701-2001], 2000 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Univ. Council Committee on the Library Preservation Sub-Committee, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Social Science 1981 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Stastics Library 1981 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Yale Conservation Project, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Yale Records
    - Arbitrations, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - Archives/Management C (AMC), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Automation, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Avery, 1978, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - AYA [Association of Yale Alumni] Pres. Talk 10/23/87, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - Barcodes, 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Bibliography, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Book Handling, 1983, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Book Marks [sic] (Pres.), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Cataloging Continuation Committee Report, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Cataloging, 1983-1989 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - CCL, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - CD Council, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Circulate, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Clearwater, 1979, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Collection Development, 1985, 1987, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - CIS, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Communication, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Computers, 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Computer Equipment, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Computer Hardware (RLG), 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Computer Software, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 188)
  - Reference
    - Conservation Articles, 1981, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Abbey Publications, Undated (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - ABEL, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Access and Pres., 1988 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Acidity Tests -- Paper, 1977, 1983 (articles); 1981-1982, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - ACLS, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Acme Bookbinding Company, Inc., Undated (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - ACQ Working / Support Group, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - ACRL, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Addresses, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - Adhesives, 1979, 1982 (article) (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - AIC [American Institute for Conservation], 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Akaline Paper, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - ANSI Paper Standard, 1983-1984, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Archival Products, 1983, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Archives (Pres), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - ARL Min. Pres. Effort, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Asbestos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 206)
    - AV Materials, 1983, 1988, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - AV Materials -- Preservation, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - Banks -- Deterioration, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - Berger, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - Bibliographers / Curators, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Bibliog. Control of Microforms, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Bibliographies, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - Bindery / Bridgeport, Undated (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Binding Eqpt. Vendors, Undated (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Book Drops, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 216)
    - Booklab, Undated (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Boston Library Consortium, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - Boxes (Microfilm), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - British Library, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - British Book Replacement Services See Teleprint (sp?), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Buildings and Conservation, 1983, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - CD-ROM, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - CD-ROM, 1987, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - Center for British Art -- Conserv. Lab, Undated (Box 6, Folder 225)
    - Chadwick-Healey, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Collection Conservation / Conservators, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Color Microform, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Other Conservation Programs, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Pres. Policy / Needs Assessment, 1998, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Columbia, Undated (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - [Council on Library Resources Bound Periodical #171] [not in a folder], 1962 (Box 6)
    - Cataloging in RLIN, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - [loose papers], 1979, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 233)
    - Articles on Preservation, 1960s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - Bibliography -- Preservation, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Binding Articles, 1951, 1967-1980 (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Binding Articles and Reports, 1966-1977 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - Binding Developments, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - Binding Training Programs, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - Equipment Preservation, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 240)
    - Gaseous Diffusion Barrow, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 241)
    - Binding Methods, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - LC Preservation Leaflets and Program, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - Lighting, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Microfilm -- Quality Control, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Microform Equipment, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 246)
    - [Report titled "Conservation in Libraries," by Koel -- not in a folder], 1981 (Box 7)
    - Fun Quotations, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 247)
    - Microforms -- Diaz Book, Circa 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 248)
    - Microforms -- STDS, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 249)
    - Mylar, 1973, 1979, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 250)
    - National Preservation Proposals, 1966, 1969, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 251)
    - NEDCC, 1970, 1983, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 252)
    - NRMM, 1974, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 253)
    - OP Booksearching, 1968, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 254)
    - Photographs -- Preservation, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 255)
    - Preservation Programs, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 256)
    - Repair, 1966, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 257)
    - RGD -- Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 258)
    - Reprinting, 1973-1981 (Box 7, Folder 259)
    - Restoration Techniques, 1965-1981 (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - RPI, 1971-1977 (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - Illinois Coop. Cons., 1982 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - Salvage of Water Damaged Books… Lundquist, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - Storage, Undated (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Sound Recordings, Undated (Box 7, Folder 266)
    - Stanford Preservation, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 267)
    - Tape, Cassette, etc., Preservation, 1970, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 268)
    - USBE (United States Book Exchange), 1972-1973, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 269)
    - RLG -- Stanford Preservation, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 270)
    - Reels, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 271)
    - Paper Standards (mostly reference materials, plus some correspondence about paper standards) (Box 7, Folder 272)
    - Assorted loose pages of reference materials, plus some correspondence about paper standards, 1959, 1970, 1976-1980 (Box 7)
  - Policies and Procedures
    - Beinecke Rules 1964-1974, 1965, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 359)
    - Emergencies, 1968-1979 (Box 8, Folder 360)
    - Housekeeping -- Maint. Stacks Preservation, 1971-1978 (Box 8, Folder 361)
    - Deacidification 1 step, 2 step [sic], 1972, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 362)
    - Microform Task Force, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 363)
    - (Master) Microform Pricing Implementation, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 364)
    - Orientation Talks, 1979, 1981-1987 (Box 8, Folder 365)
    - Yale -- Petitions Implementation Wmson. [Williamson] Task Force RLG, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 366)
    - Presentation Proj -- Notes [some preservation processes/procedures, some training materials, 1963, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 367)
    - Preservation Problems, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 368)
    - Replacements, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 369)
    - Speeches, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 370)
    - HEP -- 1970-1973, Undated (Box 8, Folder 371)
    - Yale Support Info. [some preservation records, some policy misc., some reference, some prof. develop.], 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 372)
    - W Collection [weeding], 1954-1963 (Box 8, Folder 373)
    - Comprehensive Preservation Microfilming Project in the Social Sciences at Yale [loose pages], Undated [1988 or later] (Box 8, Folder 374)
    - PMP Filming Instructions, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 375)
  - Budget and Finance
    - Budget, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - Expenses, 1969, 1973-1978 (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Freezing, 1974, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 275)
    - Photocopy Inter-Departmental Charges, 1986-1992 (Box 22, Folder 276)
    - Annual Report, 1971-1977 (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - Commercial Microfilm Service, Inc. (PMP Costs) [loose page], 1985 (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - Microform Report Implementation, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 279)
    - PMP Reimbursements, 1986-1991 (Box 22, Folder 280)
    - GCMP III Rainbow Sheets, 1992-1993 (Box 22, Folder 281)
    - GCMP III Msc. Bills, 1992-1993 (Box 22, Folder 282)
    - ATLA [American Theological Library Association] -Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 283)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes Preservation Dept. staffing costs, plus an ATLA NEH application
    - Miscellaneous Files to Keep (alphabetized files amassed from several boxes; need to be inter-filed)
      - Accounts, 1987-1989 (Box 23, Folder 312)
      - Advanced Preservation Planning Article, 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 313)
      - Africana Collection, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 314)
      - Annex Move, 1978-1983 (Box 23, Folder 315)
      - A.O.S., 1980, 1983, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 316)
      - Archival Photocopying and Preservation Decision-Making [sic], 1986-1987 (Box 23, Folder 317)
      - ARL Microform Cataloging Guidelines, 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 318)
      - ARL / OMS [Office of Management Studies], 1985-1989 (Box 23, Folder 319)
      - ARL Talk -- Pres. Planning, 1987 October (Box 23, Folder 320)
      - ARL, 1981-1991 (Box 23, Folder 321)
      - ARL Stat. (Survey), 1984-1992 (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - ARL Preservation Survey, 1984-1989 [stet] (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - ARL Spec Kit -- Brittle Books, 1987-1989 (Box 23, Folder 324)
      - Art Library, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 325)
      - Arts of the Book, 1979, 1980, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 326)
      - Assessing Needs -- State of Collection 30 min., 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 327)
      - ATLA [American Theological Library Association] -- Proposal, 1978-1992 (Box 23, Folder 328)
      - Automating, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 329)
      - Automation and Preservation: Talk ALA Annual, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 330)
      - Bagnall [editorial by Roger S. Bagnall in the Yale Alumni Magazine, December 1987], 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 331)
      - Bibliographer's Aid Notebook [guidelines for decision making about preservation of books], 1985-1987 (Box 23, Folder 333)
      - Boston Speech -- Acq. and Bibl., 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 334)
      - Bridgeport Nat'l Bindery [James M. Larsen, president], 1986-1989 (Box 23, Folder 335)
      - Briefing on Pres., 1986 (Box 23, Folder 336)
      - Brindex, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 337)
      - Brittle Book Workshop [intern], 1984 (Box 23, Folder 339)
      - Budget, 1983-1988 (Box 23, Folder 341)
      - Byrnes, M [Margaret] [Preservation Officer, University of Michigan], 1981-1983 (Box 23, Folder 342)
      - Care and Handling Workshop, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 343)
      - Care and Handling Workshop Extra Handouts, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 344)
      - Care and Handling Workshop -- Masters and Outlines, 1984, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 345)
      - CIC [CIC Preservation Proposal], 1987 (Box 23, Folder 346)
      - Checkpoint Security Systems, 1978-1983 (Box 23, Folder 347)
      - Circ. Workshop, 1990-1992 (Box 23, Folder 348)
      - Classics [Classics Library], 1985 (Box 23, Folder 349)
      - CLR Intern, 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 350)
      - Condition Checks, 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 351)
      - Condition Report S and D Master [re: NEH Grant 1985] (Box 23, Folder 352)
      - Conferences, 1982 (?), 1985-1988 (Box 23, Folder 353)
      - CT State Pres. TF [Task Force], 1988 (Box 23, Folder 354)
      - CONSER [CONversion of SERials Project, later renamed CONSER, for Cooperative ONline SERials], 1988 (Box 23, Folder 355)
      - Condition Survey Proposal -- UCONN, S. ILL and S. Florida, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 356)
      - Congressional Hearing, Undated (Box 23, Folder 357)
      - [unidentified folder] [Preservation Task Force], 1986-1987 (Box 23, Folder 358)
  - Preservation Records / Preservation Process
    - Binding Log Book, 1947-1953 (Box 22, Folder 284)
    - Preservation Outreach (Yale), 1984 (Box 22, Folder 285)
    - Conservation Policies, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 286)
    - Preservation Department -- History and Activities [loose pages], 1979 (Box 22)
    - Preservation Department -- Training Manual [loose pages], 1979 (?) -1980 (Box 22)
    - Yale Collection of Historical Sound Recordings -- Yale University Library [single loose page], Undated (Box 22)
    - Insurance on Library Materials [loose pages], 1975 (Box 22)
    - Intern Education Conservation Techniques [loose pages], 1981 (Box 22)
    - Disaster Workshop Attendance [loose pages], 1983-1984 (Box 22)
    - Preservation Workshop Want List, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 287)
    - Preservation Department Want List, 1980 or 1983 (Box 22, Folder 288 - 291)
    - Microform Reports, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 292)
    - Paper Testing, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 293)
    - Photocopiers, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 294)
    - Photocopying -- Preservation, 1977-1979 (Box 22, Folder 295)
    - Slide and Photograph Collection, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 296)
    - Stack Problems (A/C), 1985 (Box 22, Folder 297)
    - Sterling Stacks, 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 298)
    - Preservation at Yale -- History, 1977-1979, 1981, 1983, 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 299)